

Get In Touch

hello@klemire.com www.klemire.com 904.562.9172

Address

1237 W Carmen Ave. Apt 2n Chicago, IL 60640

Technologies

- React
- GraphQL
- JavaScript
- · Node.js
- MySQL
- · Adobe XD
- Adobe Photoshop

Disciplines

- Web Development
- · Web Content Accessibility
- UI Wireframing & Design
- React Consulting

Education

University of Central Florida
BA Web Design
Aug 2012 — July 2017

Web Developer

Kyle Lemire

Experience

Dec 2020 — Present

Independent Web Development & Consulting

- Designing and building websites and applications with React, NextJS, and GatsbyJS
- Expert consultancy with front-end web development teams, teaching them React and GatsbyJS.
- Leveraging headless CMS's to deliver modern single-page applications with client-editable content.

Feb 2020 - Nov 2020

Web Developer @ Alpine Home Air

- Worked on the company's re-designed e-commerce platform using React, Redux, and server-side rendering to deliver great performance without sacrificing search engine optimization.
- Learned Lucee / Cold Fusion on the job to support the company's legacy codebase while the new site was developed.
- Implemented the re-designed front ends of industry-first tools, such as an HVAC room configurator and operating cost calculator.
- Advocated for web accessibility guidelines, influencing design and technical decisions to improve access for all customers.

Jul 2017 — Feb 2020

Web Developer @ Elyk Innovation

- Designed and developed over a dozen custom Wordpress sites from the ground up.
- Worked one-on-one with clients and trained them to maintain and update their content.
- Designed and developed a private e-commerce platform exclusively for the client's customer base, facilitating toner sales to over 3000 locations nationwide.

Personal Profile

I'm a web developer with over 3 years of professional experience eager to expand my skills and build a better, more accessible web. I'm looking for a company that believes accessible design is good design and I look forward to applying my skills to help that company succeed in their mission.